Preliminary Inventory to the Willys Ruggles Peck Papers, 1911-1952.
Hoover Institution Archives
Willys Ruggles Peck Papers
1911-1952.
53005
Hoover Institution Archives
3 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 envelope (2.2 linear feet)
Diary, correspondence, memoranda, biography, and clippings, relating to Chinese foreign relations, domestic politics in China, and the Japanese occupation in Bangkok, Thailand, during World War II.
Peck, Willys Ruggles, 1882-1952.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1953
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
United States. Dept. of State.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--Politics and government--1912-1949.; China.; Diplomats--United States.; Sino-Japanese Conflict, 1937-1945.; Thailand--Foreign relations--United States.; Thailand.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; United States--Foreign relations--Thailand.; United States--Foreign relations.; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--East Asia.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945--Thailand.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Notebook containing informal observations made by Willys R. Peck, while Consul General and Counselor of the Legation at Nanking, China in the 1930's (Box 1)
- Typescript of a biography of Willys R. Peck, co-authored by the surviving "Peck children," Willys, Llewellyn, and Mary Peck Read
- Original draft copies, with corrections, of the biography of W. R. Peck
- One typewritten letter between the Peck relatives concerning Willys Peck's biography, 1952 August 1
- One handwritten letter from one of the Peck relatives to another (mother to daughter), Peking, 1952 January 4
- INCREMENT - April 1978 (Box 2)
  - Diary of events in the American Legation, Bangkok, Thailand, 1941 December 8 - 1942 August 19
  - Printed material
  - Newspaper clippings, 1940-1945
  - Maps of China and the Philippine Islands
  - File of material on Tsingtao, China, 1917-1919 (Box 3)
  - Handwritten manuscript entitled "Life of a Prisoner at the Present Time" (former Civil Commissioner M. G. R. Gunther), 1916 July 26
  - Handwritten manuscript entitled "Wives of Prisoners," ca. 1916
  - News Bulletin, Tsingtao, 1914 September 20
  - Newspaper clipping from Peking and Tientsin Times, 1913 May 3
  - Correspondence, 1926-1943
  - Miscellaneous memoranda, newspaper clippings, copies of speeches, notes, correspondence, etc., 1911-1943
  - Chinese language materials (phrase book, flash cards, note cards, anagram game, etc.)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - Photographs. 1 print of T.K. Chang, William L. Montgomery, Willys R. Peck in San Francisco, California. (Envelope A)